Allen Collection of Frank O'Hara Letters
© 2006 University of Connecticut
Allen Collection of Frank O'Hara Letters.
1950-1966.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Allen, Donald [Collector].
1 linear foot.
Typewritten transcriptions by Donald Allen of Frank O'Hara letters. Allen collected and transcribed the letters while preparing and editing The Collected Poems of Frank O'Hara.
MSS19760001
Biography
Scope and Content
Typewritten transcriptions by Donald Allen of Frank O'Hara letters. Allen collected and transcribed the letters while preparing and editing The Collected Poems of Frank O'Hara.
Arrangement
Series I: Letters ( 1950-1966 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to [children's literature and associated artwork, nursing education and leadership, literature, various aspects of Connecticut history, Connecticut labor, Connecticut nursing education, New England railroad, Connecticut business records, Connecticut politics, the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students, etc.]. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Organizations:
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photocopies.
Occupations:
Author.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Detailed Description
- Series I: Letters, 1950-1966
  - 1950
    - Lawrence Osgood (from Cambridge), June 23 (Other 1:3)
    - Lawrence Osgood (from Cambridge), August 2 (Other 1:6)
    - Lawrence Osgood (from Cambridge), August 31 (Other 1:11)
    - Lawrence Osgood (from Michigan), September 27 (Other 1:20)
    - Lawrence Osgood (from Michigan), October 19 (Other 1:26)
  - 1951
    - Jane Freilicher (from Michigan), March 8 (Other 1:29)
    - George Scouffas (from Michigan), April 24 (Other 1:32)
    - Lawrence Osgood (from Michigan), "late spring" (Other 1:33)
    - Jane Freilicher (one page out of sequence), "late spring" (Other 1:34)
    - Jane Freilicher (from Michigan), June 6 (Other 1:35)
    - Jane Freilicher (from Michigan), July 6 (Other 1:45)
    - Larry Rivers (from Michigan), July (Other 1:47)
    - Jane Freilicher (from Michigan), August 1 (Other 1:48)
    - Jane Freilicher (from Michigan), Summer (Other 1:51)
  - New York, 1952
    - Mrs. Arabel Porter, January 16 (Other 1:52)
    - Barbara Guest, May (Other 1:54)
    - Jane Freilicher, August 8 (Other 1:55)
  - 1953
    - Kerker Quinn, February 26 (Other 1:59)
    - Larry Rivers, June 27 (Other 1:60)
    - Kenneth Koch, September 16 (Other 1:68)
    - Larry Rivers, Autumn (Other 1:69)
    - The Porters, October 20 (Other 1:71)
    - Robert Fizdale, within 15 minutes of November 3 (Other 1:72)
    - Robert Fizdale, December 26 (Other 1:75)
  - 1954
    - Morton Feldman, January 2 (Other 1:76)
    - Anne Porter, January (Other 1:77)
    - Ned Rorem, January (Other 1:78)
    - Jane Freilicher, January 19 (Other 1:79)
    - Kenneth Koch, February 16 (Other 1:82)
    - Jane Freilicher, February 23 (Other 1:84)
    - Jane Freilicher, March (Other 1:87)
    - Ben Weber, March 20 (Other 1:89)
    - Ned Rorem, April 20 (Other 1:91)
    - Kerker Quinn, April 27 (Other 1:93)
    - Jane Freilicher, April (Other 1:94)
    - The Porters, May 1 (Other 1:97)
    - Grace Hartigan, May 21 (Other 1:98)
    - Fairfield Porter, June 25 (Other 1:103)
    - Howard Kanovitz and Marilyn Meeker, July 7 (Other 1:105)
    - Larry Rivers, July 13 (Other 1:107)
    - Fairfield Porter, August 5 (Other 1:110)
    - Kenneth Koch, August 14 (Other 1:112)
    - Kenneth Koch (from O'Hara and Ashbery), November 26 (Other 1:115)
  - 1955
    - Fairfield Porter, February 2 (Other 1:116)
    - The Porters, April 4 (Other 1:117)
    - Ned Rorem, April 8 (Other 1:118)
    - Kenneth Koch, April 22 (Other 1:121)
    - Kenneth Koch, May 9 (Other 1:123)
    - Ned Rorem, May 10 (Other 1:125)
    - Kenneth Koch, May 23 (Other 1:129)
    - The Porters, June 1 (Other 1:131)
    - Kenneth Koch, June 6 (Other 1:132)
    - Fairfield and Anne Porter, June 9 (Other 1:134)
    - The Kochs, June 23 (Other 1:136)
    - Kenneth Koch, June 30 (Other 1:137)
    - Fairfield Porter, July 7 (Other 1:139)
    - Fairfield Porter, July 20 (Other 1:143)
    - The Porters, August 8 (Other 1:145)
    - Barbara Guest (from Maine with Porters), August 21 (Other 1:146)
    - Grace Hartigan, September 12 (Other 1:149)
    - The Porters, September 12 (Other 1:150)
    - The Porters, October 3 (Other 1:151)
    - Fairfield Porter, October 7 (Other 1:153)
    - Howard Griffin, October 14 (Other 1:154)
    - George Montgomery, November 9 (Other 1:156)
    - Ben Weber, November 14 (Other 1:158)
  - 1956
    - Joe LeSueur, January 5 (Other 1:1)
    - The Kochs (from Cambridge), January 9 (Other 1:4)
    - Grace Hartigan (from Cambridge), January 11 (Other 1:6)
    - The Porters (from Cambridge), January 26 (Other 1:8)
    - Grace Hartigan (from Cambridge), January 30 (Other 1:)
    - Barney Rosset (from Cambridge), February 7 (Other 1:13)
    - Grace Hartigan (from Cambridge), February 10 (Other 1:14)
    - James Schuyler> (from Cambridge), February 11 (Other 1:18)
    - The Kochs (from Cambridge), February 12 (Other 1:24)
    - Michael Goldberg (from Cambridge), February 16 (Other 1:26)
    - Barney Rosset (from Cambridge), February 29 (Other 1:30)
    - Kenneth Koch (from Cambridge), April (Other 1:31)
    - Barney Rosset (from Cambridge), April 9 (Other 1:33)
    - Barney Rosset (from Cambridge), April 18 (Other 1:35)
    - Kenneth Koch (from Cambridge), April (Other 1:37)
    - Barney Rosset (from Cambridge), May 2 (Other 1:38)
    - Joan Mitchell (from Cambridge), May 4 (Other 1:39)
    - Kenneth Koch (from Cambridge), May 6 (Other 1:41)
    - John Button, June 12 (Other 1:46)
    - James Schuyler (from Sandwich, New Hampshire), June 15 (Other 1:48)
    - Ben Weber (from Cambridge), June 18 (Other 1:53)
    - Kenneth Koch, June 26 (Other 1:54)
    - Ben Weber (from Cambridge), August 2 (Other 1:55)
    - Barney Rosset, August 16 (Other 1:56)
    - Larry Osgood, August 20 (Other 1:57)
    - Barney Rosset, August 21 (Other 1:59)
    - Barney Rosset, September 19 (Other 1:60)
    - Larry Rivers, September 28 (Other 1:63)
    - Grace Hartigan, October (Other 1:65)
    - The Kochs, December (Other 1:66)
    - Roger Shattuck, late (Other 1:68)
  - 1957
    - Larry Rivers, January 7 (Other 1:71)
    - The Kochs, January 10 (Other 1:72)
    - Judith Schmidt, January 18 (Other 1:74)
    - Arabel Porter, January 29 (Other 1:75)
    - The Kochs, January 29 (Other 1:76)
    - John Ashbery, March 27 (Other 1:78)
    - Ted Weiss, March 28 (Other 1:82)
    - Helen Frankenthaler, April 8 (Other 1:83)
    - Larry Rivers, April 8 (Other 1:84)
    - Barney Rosset, May 13 (Other 1:87)
    - John Ashbery, May 14 (Other 1:88)
    - Grace Hartigan, June 3 (Other 1:90)
    - Grace Hartigan, June 10 (Other 1:92)
    - Ned Rorem, June 12 (Other 1:94)
    - Grace Hartigan, July 2 (Other 1:95)
    - Larry Rivers, July 16 (Other 1:97)
    - The Kochs, July 25 (Other 1:99)
    - John Ashbery, July 24 (Other 1:101)
    - Mike Goldberg, August 26 (Other 1:103)
    - Don Allen, August 27 (Other 1:107)
    - Larry Rivers, September 19 (Other 1:109)
    - Grace Hartigan, December 20 (Other 1:112)
  - 1958
    - Don Allen, February 10 (Other 1:115)
    - Barbara Guest, March 9 (Other 1:116)
    - Gregory Corso, March 20 (Other 1:118)
    - Irma Hurley, April 21 (Other 1:120)
    - Don Allen, May 15 (Other 1:121)
    - Editors of Encounter, May 20 (Other 1:122)
    - Judith Schmidt, May 20 (Other 1:123)
    - Kenneth Koch, June 16 (Other 1:124)
    - Don Allen, July 16 (Other 1:126)
    - Hal Fondren, July 19 (Other 1:127)
    - Grace Hartigan (from Rome), August 19 (Other 1:130)
    - Don Allen (from Rome), August 20 (Other 1:133)
    - Barbara Guest, September 14 (Other 1:135)
    - John Ashbery, October 10 (Other 1:136)
    - Allen Ginsberg, November 11 (Other 1:139)
    - John Ashbery, December 19 (Other 1:140)
    - John Ashbery, December 22 (Other 1:143)
    - Gregory Corso, December 29 (Other 1:146)
  - 1959
    - Joe LeSueur (from Paris), January 17 (Other 1:147)
    - John Ashbery, January 26 (Other 1:150)
    - Gregory Corso, February 11 (Other 1:153)
    - Allen Ginsberg, February 20 (Other 1:154)
    - John Ashbery and Pierre Martory, March 16 (Other 1:157)
    - Don Allen, March 25 (Other 1:164)
    - Barbara Guest, April 20 (Other 1:166)
    - Grace Hartigan, May 27 (Other 1:167)
    - Allen Ginsberg and Peter Orlovsky, June 1 (Other 1:169)
    - Grace Hartigan, June 4 (Other 1:170)
    - John Ashbery and Pierre Martory, July 14 (Other 1:171)
    - Joan Mitchell, July 27 (Other 1:174)
    - The Kochs and James Schuyler, August 11 (Other 1:178)
    - James Schuyler, August 12 (Other 1:179)
    - Barbara Guest, August 17 (Other 1:181)
    - The Kochs, August 31 (Other 1:183)
    - Cable to Nell Blaine (Other 1:185)
    - Larry Rivers, September 2 (Other 1:186)
    - John Ashbery and Pierre Martory, October 2 (Other 1:187)
    - Joan Mitchell, October 2 (Other 1:190)
    - Pierre Martory, October 6 (Other 1:191B)
    - John Ashbery, October 13 (Other 1:192)
    - Ned Rorem, October 16 (Other 1:195)
    - Barbara Guest, October 19 (Other 1:198)
    - John Ashbery, October 29 (Other 1:201)
    - Joan Mitchell, November 12 (Other 1:204)
    - Barbara Guest, December 4 (Other 1:206)
    - Joan Mitchell, December 7 (Other 1:210)
    - Helen Frankenthaler, December 16 (Other 1:212)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, December 18 (Other 1:214)
    - Helen Frankenthaler, December 18 (Other 1:215)
    - James Schuyler, December 23 (Other 1:216)
    - John Ashbery, December 30 (Other 1:217)
    - Ford Foundation Statement, late (Other 1:219)
  - 1960
    - Don Allen, January 13 (Other 1:1)
    - John Ashbery, March 8 (Other 1:3)
    - John Ashbery, March 14 (Other 1:6)
    - John Ashbery, March 17 (Other 1:9)
    - Vincent Warren (from Spain), March 23 (Other 1:10)
    - Don Allen, March 23 (Other 1:11)
    - Grace Hartigan, March 23 (Other 1:12)
    - Vincent Warren, March 26 (Other 1:14)
    - Vincent Warren, April 2 (Other 1:21)
    - Ruth Witt-Diamant, April 25 (Other 1:31)
    - Don Allen, April 28 (Other 1:32)
    - John Ashbery, April (Other 1:33)
    - John Ashbery, May 9 (Other 1:37)
    - Tatyana Grosman, May 13 (Other 1:40)
    - Ned Rorem, May 13 (Other 1:41)
    - John Ashbery, June 20 (Other 1:43)
    - Vincent Warren, June 23 (Other 1:47)
    - Vincent Warren, June 24 (Other 1:50)
    - Vincent Warren, June 27 (Other 1:53)
    - Vincent Warren, June 28 (Other 1:56)
    - Vincent Warren, June 30 (Other 1:58)
    - Vincent Warren, July 1 (Other 1:62)
    - Vincent Warren, July 6 (Other 1:66)
    - Vincent Warren, July 7 (Other 1:68)
    - Vincent Warren, July 11 (Other 1:70)
    - Don Allen, July 12 (Other 1:74)
    - John Ashbery, July 14 (Other 1:76)
    - Vincent Warren, July 14 (Other 1:77)
    - Vincent Warren, July17 (Other 1:79)
    - Vincent Warren, July 18 (Other 1:85)
    - Vincent Warren, July 26 (Other 1:88)
    - Grace Hartigan, July 27 (Other 1:90)
    - Kenneth Koch, July 28 (Other 1:93)
    - Larry Rivers, July 29 (Other 1:96)
    - Vincent Warren, July 29 (Other 1:98)
    - Vincent Warren, August 2 (Other 1:100)
    - Vincent Warren, August 5 (Other 1:102)
    - Larry Rivers, August 10 (Other 1:107)
    - Larry Rivers, August 11 (Other 1:108)
    - Don Allen, September 12 (Other 1:109)
    - John Ashbery, September 21 (Other 1:111)
    - John Ashbery, September 30 (Other 1:116)
    - John Ashbery, October 14 (Other 1:119)
    - Ned Rorem, December 21 (Other 1:123)
  - 1961
    - Vincent Warren, January 16 (Other 2:1)
    - Vincent Warren, January 17 (Other 2:3)
    - Vincent Warren, January 18 (Other 2:8)
    - Vincent Warren, January 23 (Other 2:10)
    - Ruth Witt-Diamant, January 25 (Other 2:15)
    - Don Allen, January 27 (Other 2:17)
    - Vincent Warren, January 27 (Other 2:19)
    - Ruth Witt-Diamant, January 30 (Other 2:21)
    - John Ashbery, February 1 (Other 2:22)
    - Don Allen, February 8 (Other 2:32)
    - Vincent Warren, February 9 (Other 2:33)
    - Vincent Warren, February 10 (Other 2:36)
    - Allen Ginsberg, February 13 (Other 2:38)
    - Vincent Warren, February 14 (Other 2:39)
    - Joan Mitchell, February 23 (Other 2:41)
    - Vincent Warren, February 27 (Other 2:44)
    - Vincent Warren, February 28 (Other 2:47)
    - Vincent Warren, March 1 (Other 2:50)
    - Vincent Warren, March 2 (Other 2:52)
    - Vincent Warren, March 4 (Other 2:55)
    - Vincent Warren, March 6 (Other 2:58)
    - John Ashbery, March 8 (Other 2:62)
    - Peter Orlovsky, March 23 (Other 2:65)
    - John Ashbery, May 1 (Other 2:67)
    - Barbara Guest, May 19 (Other 2:73)
    - Barbara Guest, May 22 (Other 2:74)
    - Vincent Warren, June 7 (Other 2:76)
    - Vincent Warren, June 22 (Other 2:78)
    - Barbara Guest, July 5 (Other 2:80)
    - Larry Rivers, July 5 (Other 2:81)
    - John Ashbery, July 10 (Other 2:83)
    - Vincent Warren, July 17 (Other 2:87)
    - Larry Rivers, July 18 (Other 2:91)
    - John Ashbery, July 18 (Other 2:92)
    - Vincent Warren, July 21 (Other 2:98)
    - Larry Rivers, July 21 (Other 2:100)
    - Barbara Guest, July 24 (Other 2:103)
    - Larry Rivers, July 24 (Other 2:105)
    - Larry Rivers, July 28 (Other 2:106)
    - Richard Miller, July 28 (Other 2:108)
    - Vincent Warren, August 17 (Other 2:110)
    - Peter Boneham, August 25 (Other 2:112)
    - Larry Rivers, September 7 (Other 2:114)
    - John Ashbery, September 20 (Other 2:115)
    - Don Allen, September 20 (Other 2:116)
    - John Ashbery, September 20 (Other 2:120)
    - John Ashbery, September 29 (Other 2:125)
    - John Ashbery, October 16 (Other 2:129)
    - Open Letter in support of Floating Bear, October 21 (Other 2:132)
    - Larry Rivers (from Rome), November 11 (Other 2:134)
    - John Ashbery, December 7 (Other 2:135)
    - Vincent Warren, December 10 (Other 2:141)
    - Don Allen, December 15 (Other 2:143)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, December 17 (Other 2:147)
    - Vincent Warren, December 18 (Other 2:148)
  - 1962
    - Vincent Warren, January 2 (Other 2:1)
    - Larry Rivers, January 3 (Other 2:3)
    - Vincent Warren, January 8 (Other 2:6)
    - John Ashbery, January 8 (Other 2:8b)
    - Larry Rivers, January 15 (Other 2:9)
    - Vincent Warren, January 19 (Other 2:12)
    - Bill Berkson, January 31 (Other 2:17)
    - Vincent Warren, February 5 (Other 2:18)
    - Peter Boneham, February 11 (Other 2:19)
    - Vincent Warren, February 15 (Other 2:24)
    - Vincent Warren, March 2 (Other 2:29)
    - John Ashbery, March 9 (Other 2:36)
    - Vincent Warren, March 13 (Other 2:39)
    - Vincent Warren, March 15 (Other 2:44)
    - Larry Rivers, March 23 (Other 2:45)
    - John Ashbery, April 11 (Other 2:47)
    - John Ashbery, April 20 (Other 2:51)
    - Larry Rivers, April 27 (Other 2:55)
    - Larry Rivers, May 28 (Other 2:59)
    - Larry Rivers, June 11 (Other 2:61)
    - Tanya Grosman, June 20 (Other 2:63)
    - Bill Berkson, July 10 (Other 2:64)
    - Larry Rivers, July 30 (Other 2:69)
    - Bill Berkson, August 12 (Other 2:72)
    - Don Allen, August 18 (Other 2:77)
    - David Shapiro, September 10 (Other 2:83)
    - John Ashbery, September 11 (Other 2:85)
    - Larry Rivers, October 4 (Other 2:89)
    - Vincent Warren, October 27 (Other 2:92)
    - Larry Rivers, October 29 (Other 2:97)
    - Joan Mitchell, November 11 (Other 2:102)
    - John Ashbery, November 20 (Other 2:105)
    - David Shapiro, December 3 (Other 2:108)
    - Vincent Warren, December 3 (Other 2:109)
    - David Shapiro, December 6 (Other 2:111)
    - Vincent Warren, December 30 (Other 2:112)
  - 1963
    - Philip O'Hara, January 11 (Other 2:1)
    - Vincent Warren, January 12 (Other 2:4)
    - Larry Rivers, January 18 (Other 2:8)
    - Frank Lima, February 6 (Other 2:9)
    - John Ashbery, February 7 (Other 2:12)
    - Bill Berkson, February 19 (Other 2:14)
    - Maxine Groffsky, March 16 (Other 2:16)
    - Gerard Malanga (Other 2:25)
    - Larry Rivers, April 7 (Other 2:26)
    - Larry Rivers, April 20 (Other 2:30)
    - Larry Rivers, May 15 (Other 2:34)
    - Larry Rivers, June 4 (Other 2:35)
    - John Ashbery, June 14 (Other 2:37)
    - Larry Rivers, June 19 (Other 2:41)
    - Larry Rivers, June 30 (Other 2:42)
    - Larry Rivers, July 21 (Other 2:44)
    - Don Allen, August 26 (Other 2:46)
    - Joan Mitchell, August 28 (Other 2:48)
    - John Ashbery, August 30 (Other 2:52)
    - John Myers, September 1 (Other 2:55)
    - Renee Neu, September 18 (Other 2:56)
    - Vincent Warren, September 18 (Other 2:57)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, September 25 (Other 2:59)
    - Joe LeSueur, September 30 (Other 2:62)
    - Barbara Guest (from Paris), October 14 (Other 2:67)
    - Mike Goldberg (from Rome), November 11 (Other 2:68)
    - Joe LeSueur (from Belgrade), November 19 (Other 2:69)
    - Don Allen (from Vienna), November 23 (Other 2:76)
  - 1964
    - John Ashbery, January 21 (Other 2:78)
    - John Ashbery, January 23 (Other 2:85)
    - Bill Berkson, January 27 (Other 2:89)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, February 3 (Other 2:92)
    - John Ashbery, February 13 (Other 2:94)
    - Lita Hornick, February 17 (Other 2:96)
    - Tanya Grosman, February 18 (Other 2:98)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, March 26 (Other 2:100)
    - Larry Rivers, April 18 (Other 2:101)
    - Jan Cremer, May 8 (Other 2:106)
    - Jan Cremer, May 8 (Other 2:107)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, June 5 (Other 2:109)
    - Vincent Warren, June 24 (Other 2:110)
    - New York Review of Books, June 30 (Other 2:112)
    - Helen Frankenthaler, July 2 (Other 2:113)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, August 29 (Other 2:115)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, September 8 (Other 2:117)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, September 18 (Other 2:119)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, October 12 (Other 2:121)
    - Mike Goldberg, October 22 (Other 2:122)
    - Mike Goldberg, November 16 (Other 2:123)
    - Mike Goldberg, November 28 (Other 2:125)
  - 1965
    - Renee Neu, March 31 (Other 2:127)
    - Lawrence Ferlinghetti, February 28 (Other 2:131)
    - John Ashbery, April 26 (Other 2:132)
    - Jack Larson and Jim Bridges, August 16 (Other 2:138)
    - Open Letter on Erje Ayden, December 20 (Other 2:139)
  - 1966
    - Joe Ceravolo, March 4 (Other 2:140)
    - Vincent Warren, March 24 (Other 2:143)
    - Vincent Warren (from Arnhem), May 10 (Other 2:146)
    - Joan Mitchell (from Arnhem), May 15 (Other 2:149)
    - Bill Berkson, May 24 (Other 2:152)
    - Barnett Newman, July 15 (Other 2:153)
    - Vincent Warren, July 16 (Other 2:154)